(self.webpackChunk_N_E=self.webpackChunk_N_E||[]).push([[363],{9578:(e,t,s)=>{Promise.resolve().then(s.bind(s,5314))},7030:(e,t,s)=>{"use strict";s.d(t,{A:()=>r});var o=s(5155),a=s(7825),n=s(2051),i=s(1640);function r(){return(0,o.jsxs)("footer",{className:"mt-6 text-center text-gray-400 text-sm",children:[(0,o.jsxs)("p",{className:"mb-2",children:["Created by ",(0,o.jsx)("a",{className:"text-cyan-300",target:"_blank",href:"https://www.purutuladhar.com",children:"Puru Tuladhar"})," â€“ Sharpen your skills and keep learning!"]}),(0,o.jsxs)("a",{href:"https://tally.so/r/3N4O8W",target:"_blank",className:"text-underline",children:["Leave a ",(0,o.jsx)("span",{className:"text-cyan-300",children:"feedback"})]})," | ",(0,o.jsxs)("a",{href:"https://patreon.com/puru",target:"_blank",className:"",children:["Support me on ",(0,o.jsx)("span",{className:"text-cyan-300",children:"Patreon"})]}),(0,o.jsx)("br",{}),(0,o.jsx)("br",{}),(0,o.jsxs)("div",{className:"flex justify-center space-x-4",children:[(0,o.jsx)("a",{href:"https://twitter.com/ptuladhar3",target:"_blank",rel:"noopener noreferrer",className:"text-gray-400 hover:text-cyan-400 transition-colors duration-300","aria-label":"",children:(0,o.jsx)(a.A,{size:24})}),(0,o.jsx)("a",{href:"https://www.linkedin.com/in/ptuladhar3/",target:"_blank",rel:"noopener noreferrer",className:"text-gray-400 hover:text-cyan-400 transition-colors duration-300","aria-label":"",children:(0,o.jsx)(n.A,{size:24})}),(0,o.jsx)("a",{href:"https://github.com/tuladhar",target:"_blank",rel:"noopener noreferrer",className:"text-gray-400 hover:text-cyan-400 transition-colors duration-300","aria-label":"",children:(0,o.jsx)(i.A,{size:24})})]})]})}},6708:(e,t,s)=>{"use strict";function o(e){for(let t=e.length-1;t>0;t--){let s=Math.floor(Math.random()*(t+1));[e[t],e[s]]=[e[s],e[t]]}return e}s.d(t,{A:()=>o})},5314:(e,t,s)=>{"use strict";s.r(t),s.d(t,{default:()=>w});var o=s(5155),a=s(8803),n=s.n(a),i=s(2115),r=s(5683),l=s(6899),c=s(3239),d=s(5340),u=s(5565),m=s(4918),p=s(7030),h=s(6708);let g=[{question:"Which command would you use to create a secret from literal values?",options:["kubectl create secret my-secret --literal=key=value","kubectl create secret my-secret --from-file=key=value","kubectl create secret generic my-secret --from-literal=key=value","kubectl secret create generic my-secret --from-literal=key=value"],correctAnswers:["kubectl create secret generic my-secret --from-literal=key=value"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What does 'kubectl logs' command do?",options:["It displays events related to cluster activities","It retrieves logs from containers running in a Pod","It shows the status of all nodes in the cluster","It lists all available namespaces"],correctAnswers:["It retrieves logs from containers running in a Pod"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What is the purpose of Pod Security Admission in Kubernetes?",options:["To enforce network policies","To manage resource quotas","To enforce Pod Security Standards","To monitor cluster performance"],correctAnswers:["To enforce Pod Security Standards"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which Pod Security Standard is the most restrictive?",options:["Privileged","Restricted","Baseline","Custom"],correctAnswers:["Restricted"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What does authentication in Kubernetes primarily ensure?",options:["That network policies are enforced","That users can access the API server","That Pods are isolated from each other","That data is encrypted at rest"],correctAnswers:["That users can access the API server"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which authentication method is NOT supported by Kubernetes?",options:["X.509 client certificates","Bearer tokens","LDAP authentication","OAuth2.0"],correctAnswers:["OAuth2.0"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"In Kubernetes, what is the role of RBAC (Role-Based Access Control)?",options:["To define network policies for Pods","To manage user permissions and access to resources","To enforce security standards on images","To log audit events"],correctAnswers:["To manage user permissions and access to resources"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'kubectl auth can-i' command is used to check what?",options:["If a user can perform a specific action on a resource","'Can I create a new namespace?' checks namespace creation rights","'Can I use this command?' queries for permissions","'Can I list all Pods?' checks listing rights"],correctAnswers:["If a user can perform a specific action on a resource"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'Secrets' in Kubernetes are used for storing what type of data?",options:["Large binary files",".yaml configuration files",".json data files","Sensitive information like passwords and tokens"],correctAnswers:["Sensitive information like passwords and tokens"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'kubectl get secrets' command displays what?",options:["All available secrets in the cluster","All available secrets in a namespace","Detailed information about each secret","Only secrets with specific labels"],correctAnswers:["All available secrets in a namespace"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'Kubernetes Secrets' are stored in which format by default?",options:["Plain text","Encrypted using AES","Base64 encoded","JSON format"],correctAnswers:["Base64 encoded"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'Network Policies' are used to control what aspect of Kubernetes?",options:["Pod-to-Pod communication","User authentication","Resource allocation","Service discovery"],correctAnswers:["Pod-to-Pod communication"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What is the primary function of audit logging in Kubernetes?",options:["To monitor resource usage","To record API requests and responses","To enforce network policies","To manage user authentication"],correctAnswers:["To record API requests and responses"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which component is responsible for enforcing network policies in Kubernetes?",options:["API Server","Kubelet","Kube-Proxy","Network Plugin"],correctAnswers:["Network Plugin"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"In Kubernetes, what does isolation refer to?",options:["The separation of workloads from each other","The use of firewalls between clusters","The encryption of data at rest","The management of user permissions"],correctAnswers:["The separation of workloads from each other"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which method is commonly used to achieve isolation between Pods?",options:["Labels","Namespaces","Annotations","Taints"],correctAnswers:["Namespaces"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What does a NetworkPolicy resource define in Kubernetes?",options:["The security context for Pods","The resource limits for Pods","The allowed ingress and egress traffic for Pods","The service account permissions"],correctAnswers:["The allowed ingress and egress traffic for Pods"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What is the default behavior for Pods without any NetworkPolicy applied?",options:["They cannot communicate with any other Pods","They can only communicate with their own namespace","They can communicate only with services","They can communicate with all other Pods"],correctAnswers:["They can communicate with all other Pods"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which type of logging captures detailed information about API requests in Kubernetes?",options:["Event logging","Audit logging","Access logging","Error logging"],correctAnswers:["Audit logging"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which component is responsible for managing network traffic between services in Kubernetes?",options:["Kube-Proxy","API Server","Scheduler","Controller Manager"],correctAnswers:["Kube-Proxy"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What does 'kubectl describe pod <pod-name>' provide?",options:["A list of all containers running within the Pod","Logs generated by the Pod's containers","Detailed information about the Pod's status and configuration","Events related to the Pod's lifecycle"],correctAnswers:["Detailed information about the Pod's status and configuration"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which of the following is a recommended practice for managing Kubernetes Secrets?",options:["Store Secrets in plain text files","Use environment variables to pass Secrets","Use tools like Sealed Secrets or HashiCorp Vault","Share Secrets via email"],correctAnswers:["Use tools like Sealed Secrets or HashiCorp Vault"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What is the primary purpose of a ServiceAccount in Kubernetes?",options:["To manage user access to the cluster","To provide an identity for Pods to interact with the Kubernetes API","To define resource limits for Pods","To enforce network policies"],correctAnswers:["To provide an identity for Pods to interact with the Kubernetes API"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"'kubectl get networkpolicies' shows what?",options:["All network policies applied in the cluster","The status of all running Pods","Detailed information about each service","The number of active users in the cluster"],correctAnswers:["All network policies applied in the cluster"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Taints and Tolerations are used for what purpose in Kubernetes?",options:["To manage network policies","To control Pod scheduling on nodes","To enforce security standards","To define resource quotas"],correctAnswers:["To control Pod scheduling on nodes"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Kubernetes Audit Logs can be configured to capture which type of events?",options:["Only failed authentication attempts","All API requests made to the cluster","Pod lifecycle events only","Network traffic between Pods"],correctAnswers:["All API requests made to the cluster"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"RoleBinding in Kubernetes is used for what purpose?",options:["To bind a role to a specific namespace","To grant permissions to users or groups within a namespace","To enforce security policies on Pods","To manage network policies"],correctAnswers:["To grant permissions to users or groups within a namespace"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which command would you use to view audit logs in Kubernetes?",options:["kubectl get auditlogs","kubectl logs audit","cat /var/log/audit.log","kubectl describe audit"],correctAnswers:["cat /var/log/audit.log"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What does 'kubectl apply -f <file>' do?",options:["It applies configuration changes defined in the specified file","It deletes resources defined in the specified file","It retrieves information from the specified file","It validates the syntax of the specified file"],correctAnswers:["It applies configuration changes defined in the specified file"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which component is responsible for enforcing security contexts in Kubernetes?",options:["Kubelet","API Server","Controller Manager","Scheduler"],correctAnswers:["Kubelet"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"What is a common method for securing communication between Pods?",options:["Using Network Policies","Using RBAC","Using Secrets","Using ConfigMaps"],correctAnswers:["Using Network Policies"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which of the following are valid types of Kubernetes resources that can be managed with RBAC? (Select all that apply)",options:["Pods","Namespaces","Endpoints","ConfigMaps"],correctAnswers:["Pods","Namespaces","ConfigMaps"],multipleAllowed:!0,maxSelections:3},{question:"What is one way to encrypt Secrets at rest in Kubernetes?",options:["Using TLS certificates","Using KMS (Key Management Service)","Using Base64 encoding","Using RBAC"],correctAnswers:["Using KMS (Key Management Service)"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which of the following are valid methods for authenticating users in Kubernetes? (Select all that apply)",options:["X.509 client certificates","Bearer tokens","OpenID Connect","SSH keys"],correctAnswers:["X.509 client certificates","Bearer tokens","OpenID Connect"],multipleAllowed:!0,maxSelections:3},{question:"What is a common use case for Network Policies?",options:["Restricting access to sensitive data","Controlling traffic between different applications","Limiting resource usage by Pods","Managing user authentication"],correctAnswers:["Controlling traffic between different applications"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"When should you consider using Pod Security Policies?",options:["When you need to limit resource usage","When you want to enforce security standards on Pod specifications","When managing network traffic","When configuring service accounts"],correctAnswers:["When you want to enforce security standards on Pod specifications"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1},{question:"Which command would you use to create a Role that allows reading Pods?",options:["kubectl create role pod-reader --verb=get --resource=pods","kubectl create role pod-reader --verb=read --resource=pods","kubectl create role pod-reader --verb=list --resource=pods","kubectl create role pod-reader --verb=watch --resource=pods"],correctAnswers:["kubectl create role pod-reader --verb=get --resource=pods"],multipleAllowed:!1,maxSelections:1}],f=["A","B","C","D","E","F","G","H"],x=1e3/g.length;function w(){let[e,t]=(0,i.useState)(0),[s,a]=(0,i.useState)(0),[w,b]=(0,i.useState)([]),[y,A]=(0,i.useState)(!1),[S,v]=(0,i.useState)([]),[k,P]=(0,i.useState)(!1),[j,N]=(0,i.useState)(0),T=t=>{let s=g[e];s.multipleAllowed?w.includes(t)?b(e=>e.filter(e=>e!==t)):w.length<(s.maxSelections||1/0)&&b(e=>[...e,t]):b([t])},q=g[e],K=q.multipleAllowed&&w.length>=(q.maxSelections||1/0),C=q.multipleAllowed?w.length!==q.maxSelections:0===w.length;return(0,o.jsxs)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 min-h-screen pt-5 pb-5 flex items-center justify-center bg-[#0a0f18] bg-[radial-gradient(ellipse_80%_80%_at_50%_-20%,rgba(120,119,198,0.3),rgba(255,255,255,0))]",children:[(0,o.jsx)(n(),{id:"5aaa0a84c2479658",children:".bg-pattern{background-image:url(\"data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg width='100' height='100' viewBox='0 0 100 100' xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%3E%3Cpath d='M11 18c3.866 0 7-3.134 7-7s-3.134-7-7-7-7 3.134-7 7 3.134 7 7 7zm48 25c3.866 0 7-3.134 7-7s-3.134-7-7-7-7 3.134-7 7 3.134 7 7 7zm-43-7c1.657 0 3-1.343 3-3s-1.343-3-3-3-3 1.343-3 3 1.343 3 3 3zm63 31c1.657 0 3-1.343 3-3s-1.343-3-3-3-3 1.343-3 3 1.343 3 3 3zM34 90c1.657 0 3-1.343 3-3s-1.343-3-3-3-3 1.343-3 3 1.343 3 3 3zm56-76c1.657 0 3-1.343 3-3s-1.343-3-3-3-3 1.343-3 3 1.343 3 3 3zM12 86c2.21 0 4-1.79 4-4s-1.79-4-4-4-4 1.79-4 4 1.79 4 4 4zm28-65c2.21 0 4-1.79 4-4s-1.79-4-4-4-4 1.79-4 4 1.79 4 4 4zm23-11c2.76 0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5-5 2.24-5 5 2.24 5 5 5zm-6 60c2.21 0 4-1.79 4-4s-1.79-4-4-4-4 1.79-4 4 1.79 4 4 4zm29 22c2.76 0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5-5 2.24-5 5 2.24 5 5 5zM32 63c2.76 0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5-5 2.24-5 5 2.24 5 5 5zm57-13c2.76 0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5-5 2.24-5 5 2.24 5 5 5zm-9-21c1.105 0 2-.895 2-2s-.895-2-2-2-2 .895-2 2 .895 2 2 2zM60 91c1.105 0 2-.895 2-2s-.895-2-2-2-2 .895-2 2 .895 2 2 2zM35 41c1.105 0 2-.895 2-2s-.895-2-2-2-2 .895-2 2 .895 2 2 2zM12 60c1.105 0 2-.895 2-2s-.895-2-2-2-2 .895-2 2 .895 2 2 2z' fill='%23ffffff' fill-opacity='0.05' fill-rule='evenodd'/%3E%3C/svg%3E\")}"}),(0,o.jsxs)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 w-full max-w-2xl p-4 sm:p-6 md:p-8 border bg-[#1a1f2e]/50 shadow-lg shadow-cyan-500/20 border-cyan-800 rounded-lg",children:[(0,o.jsx)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 flex justify-center mb-6",children:(0,o.jsx)(u.default,{src:"/logo.svg",alt:"Quiz Logo",width:160,height:160,className:"rounded-3xl p-2 "})}),(0,o.jsx)("h1",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 text-3xl md:text-4xl font-bold text-center mb-6 text-transparent bg-clip-text bg-gradient-to-r from-emerald-400 via-cyan-500 to-blue-500 animate-gradient-text",children:"Kubernetes Security Fundamentals"}),(0,o.jsx)(r.N,{mode:"wait",children:y?(0,o.jsxs)(l.P.div,{initial:{opacity:0,scale:.9},animate:{opacity:1,scale:1},transition:{duration:.5},className:"text-center",children:[(0,o.jsx)("h2",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 text-2xl sm:text-3xl font-bold mb-4 sm:mb-6 text-green-300",children:"Quiz Completed!"}),(0,o.jsxs)("p",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 text-xl sm:text-2xl mb-4 sm:mb-6 text-cyan-300",children:["Your score: ",Math.round(s)," / ",1e3]}),(0,o.jsx)("p",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 "+"text-xl sm:text-2xl mb-2 ".concat(k?"text-green-300":"text-red-400"),children:k?"Congratulations! You passed with ".concat(j,"%"):"Sorry, you did not pass. You scored ".concat(j,"%")}),(0,o.jsxs)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 mt-6 sm:mt-8 text-left",children:[(0,o.jsx)("h3",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 text-lg sm:text-xl font-semibold mb-4 text-cyan-300",children:"Question Summary:"}),g.map((e,t)=>(0,o.jsxs)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 mb-4 sm:mb-6 bg-gray-700 bg-opacity-50 rounded-lg p-3 sm:p-4",children:[(0,o.jsxs)("p",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 font-medium mb-2 text-gray-100",children:[t+1,". ",e.question]}),(0,o.jsx)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 mb-2",children:e.options.map((t,s)=>(0,o.jsxs)("p",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 "+"".concat(e.correctAnswers.includes(t)?"text-green-300":"text-gray-300"),children:[f[s],". ",t]},s))}),(0,o.jsxs)("p",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 "+"flex items-center ".concat(JSON.stringify(S[t].sort())===JSON.stringify(e.correctAnswers.sort())?"text-green-300":"text-red-400"),children:["Your Answer(s): ",S[t].map(t=>f[e.options.indexOf(t)]).join(", "),JSON.stringify(S[t].sort())===JSON.stringify(e.correctAnswers.sort())?(0,o.jsx)(c.A,{className:"ml-2 w-5 h-5"}):(0,o.jsx)(d.A,{className:"ml-2 w-5 h-5"})]})]},t))]}),(0,o.jsx)("button",{onClick:()=>{t(0),a(0),b([]),A(!1),v([]),P(!1),N(0),g=(0,h.A)(g)},className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 mt-4 sm:mt-6 p-3 sm:p-4 bg-cyan-600 hover:bg-cyan-700 rounded-lg text-lg font-semibold transition-all duration-300 text-white w-full",children:"Restart Quiz"})]},"results"):(0,o.jsxs)(l.P.div,{initial:{opacity:0,y:20},animate:{opacity:1,y:0},exit:{opacity:0,y:-20},transition:{duration:.5},children:[(0,o.jsxs)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 mb-4 text-lg font-semibold  text-transparent bg-clip-text bg-gradient-to-r from-emerald-400 via-cyan-500 to-blue-500 animate-gradient-text",children:["Question ",e+1," of ",g.length]}),(0,o.jsx)("h2",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 text-xl sm:text-2xl font-bold mb-4 sm:mb-6 text-cyan-500",children:q.question}),(0,o.jsx)("div",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 grid grid-cols-1 sm:grid-cols-2 gap-3 sm:gap-4 mb-4 sm:mb-6",children:q.options.map((e,t)=>(0,o.jsxs)("button",{onClick:()=>T(e),disabled:K&&!w.includes(e),className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 "+"p-3 sm:p-4 rounded-lg text-left transition-all duration-300 ".concat(w.includes(e)?"bg-cyan-600 text-white":K?"bg-gray-600 text-gray-400 cursor-not-allowed":"bg-gray-700 hover:bg-gray-600 text-gray-100"),children:[(0,o.jsxs)("span",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 font-bold mr-2",children:[f[t],"."]})," ",e]},e))}),q.multipleAllowed&&(0,o.jsxs)("p",{className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 text-sm text-cyan-300 mb-4",children:["This question requires ",q.maxSelections," selections. You have selected ",w.length," out of ",q.maxSelections,"."]}),(0,o.jsx)("button",{onClick:()=>{let o=g[e],n=o.multipleAllowed?o.correctAnswers.every(e=>w.includes(e))&&w.length===o.correctAnswers.length:w[0]===o.correctAnswers[0];if(n&&a(s+x),v([...S,w]),e+1<g.length)t(e+1),b([]);else{let e=s+(n?x:0),t=e>=700;P(t),N(Math.round(e/1e3*100)),A(!0),t&&setTimeout(()=>{(0,m.A)({particleCount:100,spread:70,origin:{y:.6}})},500)}},disabled:C,className:"jsx-5aaa0a84c2479658 "+"w-full p-3 sm:p-4 rounded-lg text-lg font-semibold transition-all duration-300 ".concat(C?"bg-gray-700 cursor-not-allowed text-gray-400":"bg-cyan-600 hover:bg-cyan-700 text-white"),children:e===g.length-1?"Finish Quiz":"Next Question"})]},"question")}),(0,o.jsx)(p.A,{})]})]})}}},e=>{var t=t=>e(e.s=t);e.O(0,[6,379,441,517,358],()=>t(9578)),_N_E=e.O()}]);